love podcast at what age do we learn how
to have better conversations the
recording is in progress
learn hello Meredith hello Craig welcome
to the junkyard love podcast I'm really
happy you're here thanks Jacob we're
thrilled to be here so happy to be here
Jacob thank you yeah yeah I've uh I've
really enjoyed just kind of diving into
your guys's work checking out more of
your stuff I feel like you both have
such a a positive friendly vibe to I
just I feel like I have a little chip in
my in my step as I'm listening to your
stuff on my phone so I I appreciate uh
just the energy that you guys bring to
your content it's really cool oh thanks
that makes me feel so good yeah yeah
that's awesome to hear we appreciate
that that's like we that's who we are
we're we're we were approachable we're
the kind of like the the friends and
like like that's that's the vibe that
we're I'm happy to hear that we're
portraying so that's great yeah the the
old authenticity thing really works huh
yeah yeah exactly well well cool so um
get everybody else to where I'm at like
I I I'm I'm already falling for you guys
I love your work I love learning about
you um I want to bring other people
aboard so assuming other people who are
listening have never heard of you they
haven't heard of your work um there will
be a brief description below but before
they read that give them a little
Lowdown of who you are and what you're
all about lead it off okay you usually
all right well we'll give you a little a
little bit of our backstory and how we
end it up here because we are marriage
coaches relationship coaches but that is
not what we've been doing for most of
our Lives you know most most of our
Lives we learned the the default life
you know you go to school you get good
grades you get a good job so we we were
checking all those boxes living our
corporate our corporate life but also
feeling a bit like we had more to offer
the world than we were able to provide
in that corporate existence so we
weren't feeling super fulfilled in those
jobs but because that's what we' learned
you know we were checking all those
boxes and by all societies metrics we
were we were we were having a successful
a successful life from the outside
looking in and so when our company work
for the same company actually and when
our company decided to close the office
that we worked in and move everybody
across the country we were faced with a
decision we could move across the
country and keep our jobs or get
promoted and all those great things or
we could go and so it was a really
stressful decision at that time because
corporate was really all we knew even
though we weren't super happy there you
know you could tell the vibe from all of
our friends and family was well that's
the safe stable right thing to do and
even though we're very sort of tight Bay
plan oriented people we like to have a
full fully biged plan before we jump and
that was you know the old version of us
we had this feeling inside like maybe we
could jump like maybe we could and then
at the same time incredibly my dad was
diagnosed with cancer and that we we
thought it would be his last Christmas
this was 2020 and so we drove home to
spend my what we thought would be his
last Christmas with him turns out it
wasn't but on our drive back home it was
almost like that was the perspective we
needed that that last Christmas
perspective that our parents his
grandmother they're not getting any
younger and if we move all the way
across the country we're going to see a
whole lot less of them and what's really
important to us and that so that
perspective gave us what we needed to be
able to actually make the decision to
leave our corporate job so we ended up
just even though we didn't have a plan
it felt like the right decision inside
of us so we jumped out of the plane and
started trying to figure out how to
build a parachute on the way down yeah
yeah so essentially yeah we're former
corporate employees turned entrepreneurs
who are you know it's a huge mindset
shift so we're we're going through that
or we've gone through that and we
continue to go through that process and
yeah family first family oriented
obviously we wanted to be close to our
family and build a life that allowed us
to do the things that we love to do and
be around the people that we love the
most so that's that's kind of who we are
in and obviously we left that corporate
job we jumped into real estate because
we thought that that was going to be
kind of how we could replace our
corporate income kind of a little bit
quickly yeah what what happened there I
I I hear that real estate wasn't wasn't
what you thought it was going to be it
not our gy it's not our gym like yeah it
was it was um it we were miserable like
we started to go down this path and and
there was an altruistic Bend to it like
we wanted to help because the the the
housing market blew up and everywhere
including here and we wanted to help
firsttime home buyers who couldn't
afford uh T your typical mortgage we
wanted to be able to help investors
invest their money but also help those
first-time home buyers get their first
home and that was kind of near and dear
to our hearts uh and then when we start
to go down that path and do that work we
absolutely hated it and we hated it so
much that it started to like chip away
at our foundation our relationship a
little bit because historically that's
been our strength that's our superpower
that's been our Bedrock our foundation
and when we found this starting to like
chip away at that and kind of affect
that we were like time out that that's a
nogo that's a non-starter so we pulled
the pin on that like immediately and
just said no this isn't this isn't for
us which again was not an easy decision
right because we invested in a business
coach we got the website we did the
marketing we invested like a bunch of
money up front in this business that we
discovered quickly that we hated and so
six weeks later we like boarded you know
in theory boarded that thing up and said
no and so we we had that conversation
closed that business and took a step
back because we realized why we were so
miserable was that we had started a
business but hadn't yet done the work to
decide what we actually wanted our life
to look and feel like what what what did
we want our life to be like and when you
don't do that work weirdly you don't end
up building a business that supports
that Vision that you didn't create yeah
so we took a pause on trying to replace
our income and focus on the the the
revenue and the money side of things we
completely sort of put that to the side
and said okay what do we want out of
life and more importantly who do we want
to be like who are the people that we
want to be in this world and what do we
want to offer and and so we sort of
ended up falling backwards into personal
development because we went to a few
investing conferences that had a strong
personal growth vibe to them so we kind
of ended up stumbling into the personal
growth space but it was so helpful
because it helped us figure out what do
we want our life to be like and who do
we want to be and that's how we ended up
eventually finding our way to marriage
coaching because as we went to these
events these personal growth Retreats
and conferences and seminars people
would come up and ask us questions about
you know we're doing this together and
they could feel our our our bond and the
strength of our relationship so they
would how do I do this with my spouse
how do I get my wife on board how do I
get my husband to do you know so we were
answering these questions all over the
place with these people that were mostly
strangers but they were you know we're
getting to know them a little bit and
then finally we were at one of these
events and the guy hosting the event
said at my next event I want you to to
speak at the event on stage about
relationships and we were like oh maybe
we have something real to offer here and
that you know we had to codify our
situation and do a lot of research but
that that talk ended up being the
foundation for what we do now okay so
where have you guys so where you guys
started with that talk like the things
that you spoke about on stage versus
where you're at now what has ch changed
like what are the key parts that you
kept um what what are kind of the
continuous responses to questions that
people would ask you about that were
really I mean I think you've used the
word foundational a couple times I
really like that what were the
foundational questions both back then
and now that seem to be hard-hitting for
people like whoa okay that's really
something that's we should listen to
that so I I think the one of the biggest
questions we were getting at these
events was this is obvious like cuz
they' hear our story and know that we
were like basically leaving our
corporate jobs to come into
entrepreneurship and doing that together
and they they would see that and these
are a lot of entrepreneurs and people
who are kind of on that similar journey
and they' be like that's got to be
incredibly stressful how do you make
that work because there has to be so
much friction and then we started to
realize that we have some some things
that we do just naturally and then so
when we built our talk we built it on
the the pillars of how we basically
manage our relationship and so it
initially started out as three pillars
um that we've initially on that talk it
was uh the commitment to obviously
yourself you have to you have a
relationship with yourself first and
foremost you come into the World by
yourself and you leave the world Chances
Are by yourself and so the one
relationship you have from start to
finish is the one you have with yourself
so you have to be in alignment with
yourself you have to know yourself love
yourself and take care of that
relationship first and foremost so
that's the first pillar and then the
second one is the commitment to the
relationship that you're actually in
with someone so that's like your typical
like communication intimacy trust like
building on those things those are all
foundational to this relationship it's
also foundational to the relationship
with yourself but it's also foundational
to this relationship so that's one of
the pillars and then the third one is it
was a commitment to fun and adventure
and the reason that's such a pillar for
us is that you know when things stop
becoming fun you stop wanting to engage
you pull away you actually extricate
yourself from it so it has to remain fun
and there has to be a sense of adventure
and so that was the initial talk and
since then we've added a commitment to
the Future you have to have a shared
common Vision because it's one thing to
know you know you've got the commitment
to yourself the relationship and fun but
you have to know what is the vision what
is the the the shared common Vision that
we're attacking together where's what's
our Dream what are we doing and then
encompassing all that is a is a 200%
200% marriage mindset because um
marriage isn't 50/50 like it's a myth
like we we we grow up believing that
marriage is 50/50 we hear it all the
time but 50-50 leaves room for gaps like
well is that my 50% or is that your 50%
and I apologized first last time I don't
think I should this time and you did
this so I'm not going to do that and
when you get into that you get into
scorekeeping and that fractures the
relationship so it's really about having
a 100% each person giving 100 % and
taking 100% full responsibility for the
marriage wow okay yeah go those are the
pillars yeah if you have anything to add
meredi feel free no he he so those were
the three pillars we started with we
have since added the fourth pillar and
then almost like the the circle around
it all is the mindset that you need that
100% responsibility each of you taking
100% responsibility for the state for
for your marriage for the state of your
marriage yeah yeah wow that's so
powerful um Okay so backing up just a ha
when you guys were initially having
these conversations like you're both
going okay we have this change we could
move we have this potential
opportunity listen we're both not the
happiest we've ever been I mean even
being able to approach that conversation
with a level of of truth and not um I
mean I think this is such a powerful
thing about marriage
is you're your answer to those questions
could be all right how do we do this
together how do we both lean in so I
guess I'm just kind of curious how you
guys went from those seemingly probably
very difficult stressful conversations
in that moment to landing on let's lean
in harder than ever to our marriage and
do this together because I think that
you know I think that so often we could
be kind of on our own Island like like
what do I need to do and like you know
maybe my wife has it all figured out and
I what do I want to accomplish I I just
think it's so powerful and so cool
really that you guys leaned into each
other and leaned into the marriage um I
I guess if
if what message would you have for other
people having those difficult
conversations um and why would you
encourage them to lean into the
marriage I think those difficult
conversations are what is the foundation
of your marriage a lot of times I think
we're a little bit nervous of those of
those difficult conversations cuz
they're uncomfortable like having those
initial conversations about leaving the
corporate job were uncomfortable to be
to be fair we never ever contemplated
not doing it together and I think part
of that was we're either moving or we're
not so it wasn't like one of us is going
to move and keep a corporate job and one
of us is not there was a little more
Nuance to it than that where we maybe
could have done something separate but
really in we didn't really consider ever
not making the decision to together to
either keep corporate jobs find new
corporate jobs not move and find because
the third option really was we don't
move but we find new corporate jobs and
stay where we are um so there was really
three options but we never really
considered ever separating our paths I
think that was just that's just sort of
a foundational piece to our relationship
that we always feel like we're on the
same team we're in it together and
working we know we're stronger as a team
we just it wasn't even a conversation
that we had to discuss that we're
stronger as a team it was just an
inherent belief that we had that we're
stronger as a team so the conversation
was around what should we do as a team
together I I would say that it it's more
than a conversation in our situation is
that we had built the foundation and
built the bond to the point where it
just went without saying that we were on
this path together like this was this
was just us this is what we do now we
are just going to figure this out
together
I and I think that it really takes a lot
of upfront work to do that like you have
to show up every day you have to like
it's basically following the 200%
marriage mindset and being there and and
having that level of trust that the
other person is not only your teammate
but your biggest cheer leader like
they're they're there they're they're
championing you they're they're by your
side and and most of the time they're
shoulder-to-shoulder doing the thing
with you yeah and so it wasn't really
yeah necessarily a conversation as much
as we just were like okay let's just
like
strap on and let's go let's go do this
and I think to your point that building
that level of trust building that
Foundation comes from being able to have
these really honest conversations as
they come up in your life and in your
relationship and I think a lot of times
we human beings shy away from
uncomfortable conversations because
they're uncomfortable like we're we seek
Comfort like evolutionarily that's what
we do and so knowing that you're going
to have a difficult conversation you
know what's going to be uncomfortable so
a lot of times we seek the short-term
relief but that often so we we we seek
the short-term Comfort but that
oftentimes breathes long-term
dysfunction in your relationship if you
keep avoiding the difficult conversation
because it's those difficult
conversations that cement you together
every single time you decide not to
share something not to bring up
something not to have that conversation
you're putting a brick in the wall
between you and the more bricks you put
the further way you get and that's why
the most common thing we hear today is
disconnected distance walking on
eggshell and that all has come from
being unwilling to engage in a shortterm
just com uncomfortable
conversation and so when you can keep
having those uncomfortable conversations
and they don't always happen all the
time but they they come up in this the
scope of normal life when you can be
willing to have that uncomfortable
conversation when they're necessary then
you're partner feels like you're in the
Foxhole together right like we're
willing to embrace discomfort together
in the name of moving our relationship
and our life towards where we want to go
yeah I think one of the key things is
that vulnerability is actually a
superpower in your relationship so if
you can if you can get to that level and
you're open and vulnerable and sharing
the things that that are inside you with
your partner it builds that trust and it
builds that Foundation where then things
just become a little bit easier to like
in our situation where we just were like
okay let's just go and do this like
we're doing this together and it's
because we built that Foundation being
vulnerable with each other and sharing
letting each other in sharing our
deepest darkest fears Secrets dreams and
all of that so that's what it really
comes down to is building that
Foundation yeah yeah well that's so
beautiful that's so powerful I just I
love thinking about
the um you know when you make a decision
in it's in it's final it eliminates all
these other options and it just it why
it'ss your mind in a way I I was using
this example yesterday uh with my friend
I don't eat gluten and so it just
eliminates gluten from the option like I
walk down the bread aisle and I just
know I don't have to think about it I'm
not going to have any of this stuff and
so it just makes it easier for me to to
to make decisions about my food or
whatever um I think marriage can be I
mean if you have those difficult
conversations from the beginning and you
really take um you really take time to
develop kind of that conversation of
where are we headed what do we each want
out of life what do we want out of life
together
um it just kind of like takes off these
other options later on and so you
already so you come up against this
situation with you guys where you have
an opportunity to take the leap you know
and like you said build your parachute
on the way down but if you guys didn't
have that prior Foundation of hey we're
we're doing this together we're on the
same page whatever you do I do like that
that sort of thing so um my my rambling
question that I want to get to here you
two
is and I think it correlates to what
we're just talking about is what what is
the difference between what you two have
what you two have built and signing your
piece signing your name on a piece of
paper for a marriage um I think people
kind of cheap in marriage sometimes on
accident without really thinking deeply
about it and I just think it's such a
powerful relationship and commitment and
it's so much more than just signing a
piece of paper so tell me your thoughts
on that yeah I mean signing a piece of
paper is easy like it's it's very
comfortable it's very easy often times
it's very fun there's a big celebration
attached to it so we put a lot a lot of
specialness on signing that piece of
paper but signing that and and I you
know I love marriage I believe marriage
is very important I'm not diminishing
the value of being married and signing
that piece of paper but it's it's Step 1
a like it's the very teeny tiniest step
that is required to build the marriage
like being married versus building the
marriage are two very very different
things cuz you can be married but never
ever build the marriage where you feel
like you're on the same team where you
give each other the benefit of the doubt
where you're truly deeply connected and
can share all the ugly stuff and the
uncomfortable stuff even though you
don't like it you still share it because
when you do you feel like you're in it
together and you can't build that
without actually doing it you can sign a
piece of paper and it's it takes a
second and it's done you can't build the
the team team you can't build the
marriage without doing the dirty work
without doing the difficult thing
without actually doing the
stuff yeah 100% agree I don't know that
there's much I can add to that yeah yeah
M drop um okay so what is uh carrying on
with my questions here what's the north
star of your
marriage so we have now a dream life
that we have that it's a Dream Life
vision and it
um we we're type A so it's in a
spreadsheet we've got a bunch of stuff
in a spreadsheet of of things that we
want to achieve in life um and for us
it's really building a business that can
give give people the gift that we have
in our marriage we want to help as many
people as we possibly can to have this
we think it's a cheat code to life like
it it really is a cheat code when you
can have build your dream and do it with
your best friend and you can do that and
have all this energy because you're not
spending it on trying to fix problems in
your marriage or repairing your marriage
it's it's you've already done you're
doing that consistently you're doing the
maintenance on your marriage and it's in
a place where it's running really
beautifully you've got all this extra
energy to put towards your goals and
your dreams and the business the things
that you really want to do in this world
all that energy and not only just you
but your partner has all that energy and
it just exponentially grows and you can
just go further faster and so for us
really it's about equipping other
couples with a marriage of their dreams
and it may not be exactly like ours but
whatever their marriage of their dreams
is for them and helping them build their
dream life that's our ultimate North
Star is to help as many people do that
as we possibly can and to to speak about
it a little more sort of tactically like
when we built our Dream Life vision like
at the very beginning before we even got
into the coaching when we had to take
that step back we just looked at our
life and we like what do we want like
where do we want to live live what do we
want our free time to look like what do
we want the relationships in our life to
look like not just this one but with our
family and our friends and like all the
important relationships in our life what
do we want our health and vitality to
look and feel like and then what do we
want the professional the business the
that side of our life to be like and we
got separately really super crystal
clear on what the dream was and all of
those categories separately and then we
brought those dreams together to create
our shared common vision for the future
so that we had this you know joint
vision of a North star that was really
specific like when when we're doing it
it's like I can feel the breeze off the
ocean in the house we're going to build
like I'm like getting really specific in
what that dream sort of looks and feels
like so that it becomes a little bit
more real and then when you bring them
together then you have you end up with
this shared common vision and you know
exactly where you're going together so
that you're in the same boat rowing in
the same direction day by day which just
kind of inherently breeds the benefit of
the doubt and that teamwork Vibe and all
those things that we have that we want
to accomplish they're all made easier by
serving others to get theirs like that
that's the thing about this world is
like when you help people and you serve
and you get people to what they want
just just bu a byproduct is of that is
that you also achieve your North Star
and you get you get to check all those
boxes for yourself as well so yeah it is
interesting the the older I get the more
I learn more and more about service and
what it means to me and what it means
like to reality it is pretty fascinating
the the beautiful doors that open when
you just stop thinking about yourself
and just try to serve someone else it's
it's really a wonderful thing um I
wanted to ask about okay so say
someone's listening to this right now
say this is um you know the the wife in
in the in the marriage the wife in the
relationship they got a pretty good
marriage but they're listening to this
going like I you know I kind of want to
take it to the next level I want to have
these conversations we've you know we're
close but we've never really had these
deep what do you want out of life what
do you want to accomplish together um
and I don't know if this comes up often
it just kind of seems like maybe it
would but um say one person's listening
to it right now and they want to go to
their husband or their wife and say hey
I I listen to this podcast it kind of
gave me some ideas what do you think
about this what's the best approach for
that conversation would you
say I think the best approach for that
conversation is is is applying what
you're hearing ing here which is like
coming at it with a really open heart
like being a little bit vulnerable like
what well from a tactical perspective
first finding the right time like if
someone's in the middle of some kind of
chaos when you're trying to have one of
these more vulnerable
conversations the time is not right if
someone else is very distracted and in
the middle of doing something sort of
sort of very very um focused or or or
even chaotic so I think the first step
is first for sure finding the right
space the right container for this
conversation and it might be I want to
talk to you about something that I heard
today when's a good time like just
finding quiet time for both of you where
you can be connected because I think a
lot of times we're ready to have a
conversation our spouse is their mind is
completely elsewhere and we want to lay
this heavy conversation on them and it's
like whoa whoa whoa like I'm not in a
head space to rip open my heart and
share my hopes and dreams like I'm
mentally making it to-do L this or I'm
in the middle of ready an email or what
whatever it is so the first step I think
is finding the right time and space and
if there's never a perfect time in space
of course it's not about putting it off
forever but it's about when can you both
not be distracted and both be engaged
meaningfully in a conversation together
so when you can find that time in your
day so not putting it off for a week but
you can find that time today sometime
then it's leading with an open heart and
being specific like I heard this today
and this hit me because and and this is
how I'm feeling about it so speaking in
in specifics from the eye perspective
because I think a lot of times we also
sometimes have these conversations after
we've gotten frustrated with something
and it's becomes a lot of generalities
we never have these conversations we
never share this stuff I always I always
you never those types of leadin and
those types of um responses and
conversations are not effective it
creates defenses and defenses are the
last thing we want when we want to be
vulnerable and have an honest
conversation and so finding the right
time and space and then leading with how
it's impacting you and what you want to
get out of this conversation whether
that's let's sit down and listen to it
together and then we can because we do
this a lot actually if we're listening
to audio books and podcasts we do that a
lot especially when we're driving and
then it's like oh pause let's talk about
that for a minute so a lot of times it's
helpful like you got something out of
this podcast so invite your spouse along
listen to it again then you guys can
pause together and like ah this really
hit me because remember when this
happened this is actually how I was
feeling about that and so maybe we could
try and apply this and then it becomes a
really specific conversation um because
also you're coming in with that 100%
responsibility mindset and not the sort
of this is your 50% you didn't do your
job therefore I'm going to it's if you
come in with your 100% responsibility
and this is how I'm feeling and this is
what I think I need to do to show up the
best in our marriage and it would be
great if you could help me like having
those conversations and pausing through
this podcast and having those
conversations together I think that
would be really effective and I think
one other thing is just always lead with
curiosity and ask questions like I I
heard this on a podcast today and I was
wondering if you had some time I'd love
to ask you a couple questions like what
what do you see as our as your perfect
Dream Life vision and and in what what
what does your health look like like
just ask specific questions and then it
doesn't feel as though like it's a like
it's it's almost like just a
conversation like we're having it's just
questions and answers and then follow up
and it doesn't have to be this big
intimidating crazy conversation it
really can just be as simple as just ask
some questions and and then follow up
with some of your thoughts and just
before you know it you've got some sort
of a vision that you can just kind of
jot down and and kind of figure out okay
well this is what you said and this is
what I'm thinking there's a lot of
overlap here let's start building
towards this yeah you said earlier
vulnerability is a superpower in your
relationship which it is curiosity is
another superpower in your relationship
showing up with genuine curiosity will
completely transform most conversations
yeah yeah I mean I I see how your your
pillar was it the third pillar that was
uh about fun yeah yeah I see how that's
so important in that because to me like
if I was bringing up to my spouse uh
like hey there's this podcast I heard
and it made me think about my life and
it made me think about our I mean that
sounds so fun and exciting to plan out
together and like just being in that car
ride together thinking about where you
want to head and I think that's that's
massively fun that's that's a very
important pillar I love that totally
yeah um so I I uh I was kind of curious
so you guys have been how long have you
been coaching now how long have you been
like working with other people and
clients and other
marriages uh so it's 2024 so like two
and a half years nice yeah okay so so
what is coming up super commonly like
what are you hearing you guys present um
or or people come to you what is kind of
like what do they hand you when when
they come to you or what is kind of a
reoccurring theme um that that listeners
could could perhaps resonate with yeah B
big theme we hear a lot is the the
disconnection the loss of intimacy
physical or emotional but you feel like
your roommates instead of a married
couple you feel like you're walking on
eggshells afraid of of triggering the
next argument you're just feeling very
disconnected like you haven't had a real
conversation in you know a long time you
can't remember the last time you had fun
or just sat down and talked together
like that sort of theme of disconnection
I would say is humongous yeah I would
say it's the biggest one for sure yeah
you you definitely hear like within that
that the communication focus and we we
just we can't ever get in the same page
in a conversation like I say blue he
hears red and then we never can sort of
get ourselves aligned um trust is is
another one that comes up um they all
kind of come back to the same thing
they've been disconnected so the trust
isn't there because they're completely
disconnected and they haven't shown up
for each other in the way that they
could have showed up in this
relationship and so a lot of the time
it's it's really just they've they've
not put in the level of intention into
their marriage that they would and say
like their job like they go to their job
and they're very specific they have a a
set of tasks that they need to do and
they show up and they make sure that
those tasks are done well in your
marriage there's things that you have to
show up for and do and and or you're
going to get a situation where your
spous doesn't trust you because you
don't show up to do the things that they
expect should be done and so it's really
about being intentional in your marriage
like you would in other parts of your
life and and yeah so I'd say
disconnection is probably the biggest
one and I think that a lot of that comes
from you know you you got married you
signed the paper you're you built this
relationship and then you trust that
it's always going to be there and I'm
going to for now I'm going to kind of
focus over here and get my career really
ramped up or my business if you're an
entrepreneur really ramped up and like
I'm trusting that this is always going
to be here but when you stop paying
attention to something over here it it's
not always going to be there in the same
way that it was and so you have the best
most people have the best of intentions
like I love my spouse we have a great
relationship I'm going to go over here
and build this business and support my
family and be the provider that I need
to be but in the meantime over here
people are feeling unappreciated
undervalued unheard unseen disrespected
and that breeds that
disconnection yeah so so it sounds like
marriages like plants need sunlight and
water 100% exactly yeah yeah they're not
it's to your point like it's intention
and there's like certain it doesn't take
a lot of time and energy necessarily in
the maintenance phase it's it's you know
checkin questions it's making a little
bit of time every day to have an actual
conversation with your spouse to to find
the fun in your mundane daily life
activities or find the space for fun in
your life because when you think about
it when you're having fun together the
communication's flowing easily you're
feeling really connected you're intimate
your trust like all of those things feel
very easy when you're having fun and so
if you can make time to whatever you
like to do play cards go dancing like
whatever it's different for everybody
but when you can make time for those
things regularly it just it's just
maintenance it doesn't take a lot of
time and effort and then you the the
what you reap from that is just
exponential and then the one other thing
I'll say is also following through and
doing what you say you're going to
showing up when you say you're going to
show up and do the things that you say
you're going to do right that's a leads
to a lot of broken trust otherwise yeah
yeah that's a huge one that's that's a
constant work I think we're all all
working on but if we can show up and be
honest about it and um yeah
communication goes goes such a long way
so so what what is
um what what seem to be the actionable
steps that work for people I I've heard
of um I don't know if you guys have
heard of Dr Jordan Peterson uh he's like
a philosopher um but I I love the way
that he talks about his marriage I I I
admire him um he he talks about how he's
been with his wife Tammy for many many
years and they schedule things like
every week together and they're pretty
strict about it like they literally have
a room in their home for dancing
together once a week and like oh my gosh
she was talking about that I'm like what
a beautiful powerful incredible I mean
you could be annoyed the momentum of
life and all these things you got going
on and you didn't do the dishes last
night and blah blah blah but then you're
forced for a certain amount of time to
dance with someone you love in a room I
mean come on so great so so what does
that look like in your guys's world so
maybe not if you don't mind what do you
guys do in your marriage specifically
that's like scheduled planned you have
conversations you know every Monday we
sit down for this amount of time or
whatever and then what do you encourage
others to do um and even like what's the
lowest hanging fruit so even if we're
not ready to embark on this like let's
change everything about our marriage
right now what can we do today as as
people who I'm not in a relationship but
but it for people who are what small
step could they begin to take I think
one thing easy right off the bat is have
a non-negotiable date like date night
date time whatever it is whatever can
fit into your have to be a date night
yeah but like one once a week
non-negotiable this is we This Is Us
time no phones no nothing it's just you
and me doing our thing I would say easy
loow hanging fruit non-negotiable do
that and then above and beyond that we
have regular like daily check-ins where
we asked very specific question and it's
like what was the best part of your day
it's not how was is your day because how
was your day leads to fine or good or a
big you know blah of their full like a
full discourse of their whole day but
asking a very specific question of like
what was the best part of your day and
it gets you it gets them to talk to you
about what was really good about their
day and then you get to learn a little
bit about their day and you can ask them
follow-up questions but it's just a
check-in it shows that you care it shows
that if you want to be engaged in their
day they feel like you care enough to
ask something specific which promp them
to think more about the answer and give
you back something specific so not only
do you learn something about their day
and actually get to be involved in it
that they feel like you want to be so
that is just a nice way to maintain
Connection in a relationship is like
just a really specific check-in question
what's the best part of your day what
made you laugh today you know what what
was your favorite lesson you learned
today like something just specific that
prompts a thoughtful answer that can
lead to a conversation and we do that
like kind of at bedtime as we're getting
getting ready for bed like getting in
bed it's dark it's also I I find that to
be a little bit of a cheat code because
when the lights are off you're almost
you're willing to be a little more
vulnerable it feels like so you you may
answer a question slightly differently
during that time than you would if you
were doing the dishes after supper or
getting dinner ready or whatever the
case may be so I think that one is is a
one that we do every day we do have the
non-negotiable date time every week and
then a weekly connection conversation
like I like to call it a let them in
conversation and it's almost like it's
like we talked about earlier but it's
what's keeping you up at night what is
stressing you out what's got you
frustrated what are you worrying about
like how can I support you what what
what are you working toward what what's
the goals coming up because sometimes
we're a little bit afraid to share our
goals because they might seem silly or
we're afraid to share what's keeping us
up at night because we want to protect
them and it's comes with the best of
intentions um that you you don't want to
burden your spouse you know you got
something that's stressing you out at
work or with your business and you you
you know you're going to take it on you
know you're going to get it figured out
but meanwhile it's kind of eating at you
right now because it's a lot and it's
heavy but you don't want to share it
because you don't want to stress them
out either but at the same time they can
tell that you're not sharing something
the energy is a bit off and as human
beings we tend to make up stories to
fill in gaps always and so your spouse
is going to start to tell stories about
why you're not sharing things even
though you're doing it out of love and
you're trying to protect them it's
creating distance between you so I love
once a week Saturday Sunday usually over
the weekend having a conversation where
you're kind of laying bare from the week
before like the these were the highs and
lows this is what I'm working toward
this is what's keeping me up at night
this is what I'm stressing about next
week so that you kind of finish the week
together and are aligned to start the
week and there's nothing sort of in
between there's no blocks or bricks
between you to start the next week it's
a real like connection building
conversation yeah and then the one other
thing I'll say is non-negotiable hugs
whenever someone asks for a hug they
just get a hug and do and do it for 20
seconds that's when the oxytocin the
happy hormones start to release so yeah
that's a great marriage rule yeah ask
for a hug you get a hug no matter what
is happening no matter how frustrated
upset angry you know anything anybody is
if one of you asks for a hug they get a
hug always no questions asked I love
that yeah we've got a we're living with
an oxytocin producing Factory right next
to us you know sometimes we can we could
use a little of that I love that I love
that okay um let's see what else
um I okay I I was kind of I didn't know
how to how to approach this I hope it
doesn't turn into like an icky icky
corner but um I wondered me from my
perspective just being honest with you
I'm I'm a single fella I'm not in a
relationship I'm on the stinking dating
apps um modern dating is there's a
million things we could say about it I
see like so much there's so much uh like
non- monogamous relationships people
people are into um I feel like a lot of
times I'm going through the dating apps
and people just have these like long
lists of things that like you better
match these things before you even get a
date with me I don't know I'm not trying
to bring my like weird perspective or my
weird weird um experience just myself of
dating apps and in that world but I I
feel like you guys would just have good
advice so so to the person who I want to
get married I I want to have kids I want
to have a family um uh but I I don't
want to put so much pressure on on
meeting people I guess like do you have
any advice for for a 33-year-old man in
the dating Market I I suppose sure I
mean I was single for a decade before I
met him like I had a pretty serious
relationship and then I was single for a
decade and then I met him and I did the
dating app thing like I get it I hated
dating it was brutal I I I just I really
did not enjoy the dating scene and I
felt a lot of pressure from my friends
from my circles to not have such high
expectations like I was getting a lot of
from my friends you got to lower your
expectations you know there's a lot of
great people what like why aren't you
willing to settle for something that's
good enough and one boy am I glad I
didn't listen to anybody and settle like
I don't know what it was within me that
wouldn't let me settle and Cheese Louise
I am very glad I didn't settle and I
always believed there was someone out
there that would challenge me and love
me and me the way he does so my first
advice is don't settle don't settle um
and the dating apps didn't work for me
either so I I totally I totally get that
um I think the second thing is to to
take the lens of more of an adventure
like be adventurous in it um I think we
get
so Tunnel Vision on what we think we
want and we
dismiss what we think we don't want want
when if we just have the attitude of
Adventure of
like who knows this this person may or
may not be the love of my life but they
may be a really cool person I can do fun
things with or um just having a a bit
more of a open an open frame of mind and
an open lens to the value anyone can
bring to your life beyond the Romantic
relationship because I mean we were
friends first like when we met we we
didn't immediately start dating took
long enough we finally did not too long
but like long enough and so I think it
was that and everyone's kind of in
different places in their life and so
sometimes a little bit of patience is
required but I think that that lens of
Adventure um is really helpful 100% yeah
I think like taking some of that almost
like taking the edge off taking the
importance off the the the the the the
weight of it all of trying to find this
person if you just go into it with
whether this is a the person that I
spend the rest of my life with or not
either way I'm going to have a good time
I'm going to meet a friend maybe maybe
they're not even going to be a friend
but whatever it is they're in my life
for a reason and just going into it with
that attitude of Adventure and
exploration and yeah taking some of that
pressure off um but yeah it's a good
point around um yeah just just fun and
don't settle because the things that
make you you um they're non-negotiable
you can't you if if if you have value
vales and things that you hold dear you
cannot compromise those if you
compromise those ultimately you're going
to not only feel unfulfilled in the
relationship you're also going to feel
unfulfilled just as a person like inside
of you you're going to be at odds with
yourself you're going to start to not
even like yourself you're not going to
feel like yourself you're not going to
start to like yourself because you're
not actually even being you anymore so
it's really about making sure that you
do not settle
or um I guess go against your values so
funny story that I've shared a couple of
places actually and I usually talk about
it in terms of vulnerability um but I
think it also applies to what you just
said about actually showing up as
yourself and being you and letting
people sort of see you and so it was
early days we were just sort of getting
to know each other we were just talking
and that was actually the very first
sign that I was like yeah this guy
because the conversation just flowed so
easily for us that I was like there's
something special here but that's
separate um when we were having this
conversation around kind of getting to
know each other he asked me if I liked
Star Wars silly little kind of get to
know your question whatever my
interpretation of you know pop culture
is that most dudes seem to like Star
Wars I am not a giant Star Wars fan so I
was a little bit hesitant of like oh do
I tell them I don't like Star Wars like
I want him to like me because I like him
you know that that whole like wanting to
fit in and wanting to be the person I
think he wants me to be and then I had a
Moment of clarity thankfully where I
said what I'm am I going to lie about
something something hey that's kind of
silly like this like I'm going to build
this whole thing on a stupid little lie
and also if that's enough for him to say
oh I'm done with her then probably he's
not the guy for me anyway and so maybe I
will just actually be me and see if we
fit together and if we do great and if
we don't okay but if we don't then he's
obviously not the right person for me so
just be you and see how it goes and
that's not necessarily anything I had
been doing up to that point like I'm
very much a people pleaser always
wanting to fit in and so I was always
trying to be the person I thought
everyone wanted me to be and I had that
one Moment of clarity and said actually
Star Wars isn't really my jam he's like
ah me neither I was like all that mental
turmoil for nothing but I it was such an
important lesson for me in that moment
to actually not be afraid to be honest
about who I am in the silly things but
doing that made it easier for me later
with him to be more honest about the
bigger things yeah yeah yeah that um man
that's all such great advice I thank you
so much thanks for even letting me ask
that I think that's so cool um yeah you
know sometimes I get caught up in in
realizing oh I'm trying really hard or
I'm you know you're you're putting too
much wood on the fire and suffocating
the oxygen you know and so I'm always
just trying to work on um I think that's
a great note to just just have fun with
it that's what I'm trying to do here in
the end just have fun be you and it'll
happen like it it's it's the universe
has a like there's the universe is
always working in your favor it's going
to work out exactly how it's supposed to
and likely when you're least the least
amount of effort the least amount of
trying is when it's just going to like
oh boom get struck by lightning at a
random event or something that you're at
and like it'll just be like a chance
thing that and I will say as being
single for 10 years when everyone said
it'll happen when you least expected I
wanted to punch them all in the face I
always hated hearing that however I
wasn't expecting to meet him when I did
so like it kind of annoys me that it
wasn't wrong but I always hated to hear
that so I same yeah yeah yeah yeah I had
a uh a one of the older guys that I work
with kind of a few months back had given
me the same thing and I I I believe it
but I also yeah I'm with you I rolled my
eyes for sure but uh yeah for sure it's
a truth um cool well we are getting up
here in time I did have uh one more
question for you and then I would love
to just hear where we can go to find all
of your info where we could reach out um
where we could listen to more of your
stuff
uh but first before that um someone
who's listening right now maybe they
just clicked on this and they're like
this s like a cool podcast and they
listen to it and they're like uh I need
to have a conversation with my spouse I
didn't realize that I we haven't had
deep conversations in a while I don't
know where we're heading I don't know
where to open our sales of our boat at
because I don't know which wind is going
to you know where's our destination so
see someone finds thems in that position
right now what what do you have to say
to
them I think you need to have a an
honest Con well you know what before
before you even have the honest
conversation I think you need to sit
down yourself and decide what do you
actually want your dream life to be what
is your North Star where do you want to
go and then you can have that
conversation and your spouse can do the
same thing and bring those together but
I I think a lot of times we we spend the
time and we jump into the the work
together when like we talked about the
very first pillar the first commitment
is the commitment to yourself yeah and
so you know getting right with you and
being clear on okay we haven't had that
conversation on where we're headed
collectively as a as a couple as a
family
unit where do I want to be going what
like what do I see in the future for me
and for us and then once you have a
little bit of that Clarity yourself it
almost gives you a little bit of
confidence going into that conversation
um that that we need to have this
conversation together but also need to
do this work individually first and
bring those to the table so you both can
feel seen and heard and valued in that
integration conversation where you're
bringing those two visions together into
one shared common Vision
yeah I totally agree yeah I think it's
it's really just understand what you
want and then simply just ask and and
again vulnerability and curiosity yeah
get vulnerable and share what you share
your vision and get curious and ask them
about theirs and again make sure that
it's the right time and they're not
distracted but but you know set aside
some time have a have an hour set aside
distraction free no phones Just the Two
of Us face to face having a conversation
and just get vulnerable and get curious
actually I also find one little cheat
code that I think is helpful for some
more deeper conversations is to do it
while you're walking like we make sure
to go for a walk every day and the with
the blood going and being out in the
fresh air there's just something about
the creativity and also sometimes not
looking like eyeball to eyeball with
someone is less intimidating to be able
to have to share some of the stuff
that's a little less comfortable so I
think when you want to have a pretty
honest conversation of course the
vulnerability and curiosity but maybe
suggest going for a walk outside because
it just feels a little easier than
sitting down across the table from each
other that's true we do that a lot and
getting out in nature just gives you the
happy Vibes and you're in nature the
smells the the the air yeah that's
really great Point yeah yeah yeah the
the things that provide us with the
ability to breathe it feels nice to walk
past them right yeah exactly yeah it's a
it's huge I I'm I'm a huge advocate for
any sort of creative thinking or problem
solving adding a walk in and uh I also
think just to emphasize anybody
listening that having one night a week
or or one time during the week where you
designate we're putting our phones like
over here on airplane mode type thing or
whatever it is just being I mean cuz
that's when you first got together
before the all the hardship all the like
that's what it was you have the
butterflies in your stomach just having
a conversation with this person I mean
that's still there you just got to set
set some time aside so I exactly you
guys are such a wealth of information I
feel like you have given me so many
great answers um I I I'm so grateful for
your time this was so amazing this was
super fun Jacob loved it yeah super
grateful for your time as well and and
for sharing your podcast with us it's
it's amazing yeah yeah okay so so give
me the give me the load down obvious
I'll put in the description as well so
people can click on the links where can
we find you what are you working on next
um what what's on the horizon how do we
keep up with you in the
future um well we have a podcast too and
and our podcast is called the road of
Life podcast we we have more of a
bite-sized episode like 10 to 20 minutes
where we talk about sort of one concept
at a time and give a story Give an
example kind of kind of bring people
along with one strategy at a time for
your for your marriage and for your life
like a little bit of both um and I'd say
we're most active on Instagram so we're
sharing strategies and tools and tips
and and things like that um on Instagram
and we're at Meredith and Craig on
Instagram so that's where you can can
find us on there for sure yep yeah and
and if anyone wants to reach out if they
have any questions or things that are
coming up for them they can DM us
anytime and we can we can help them out
with whatever they need absolutely yeah
cool well that that's a beautiful thing
I will include all those links so
whoever's listening you can find them in
the links below Meredith Craig thank you
so much again for your time um thank you
for your wisdom and just thanks for
following your hearts and doing what you
guys do it's it's uh it's it's
contagious I feel inspired by you guys
thank you thank you so much appreciate
you yeah listeners love yourself drink
some water if you haven't drank any
water set a date day up with your
husband or your wife um and go for a
walk outside love yourselves Meredith
Craig I will be in contact soon thanks
again have a good day hello and welcome
to the junkyard love
[Music]
podcast at what age do we learn how to
have better
conversations at what age do we learn to
have better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is
power reality is
[Music]